<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jean Guegant's Blog - News</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/feeds/news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/</id><updated>2018-03-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Distributed C++ Meetup</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-20T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2018-03-20:/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in an early &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I am active member of a C++ Meetup group in Stockholm: &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/a&gt;. Last year me and the main organizer of &lt;strong&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/strong&gt; came up with the idea to gather different Meetup groups from Europe for a special event. Knowing that we are not as famous …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in an early &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I am active member of a C++ Meetup group in Stockholm: &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/a&gt;. Last year me and the main organizer of &lt;strong&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/strong&gt; came up with the idea to gather different Meetup groups from Europe for a special event. Knowing that we are not as famous as the &lt;a href="https://cppcon.org/"&gt;cppcon&lt;/a&gt;, and therefore could not attract people easily to come to visit us in our dark and cold country, we had to come up with a special plan. It happens that my current company &lt;a href="https://discover.king.com/about/"&gt;King&lt;/a&gt; has offices of decent size in few of the major tech hubs of Europe: Berlin, Stockholm, London and Barcelona. It also happens that we have pretty good video-conference facilities that we frequently use to do company-wide calls. AND It also happens that a huge share of the mobile games (Candy Crush Saga, Bubble Witch Saga...) made at &lt;strong&gt;King&lt;/strong&gt; rely heavily on a &lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt; tech stack. By using the video-conference facilities, having some drinks and food, all gently provided by &lt;strong&gt;King&lt;/strong&gt;, we were confident that we could run an event with multiple Meetup groups participating remotely and have a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus was born the concept of a &lt;strong&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We contacted the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/CppLondon/events/248091281/"&gt;London Meetup group&lt;/a&gt; and asked them if they wanted to join us in this aventure. Sure enough, Phil Nash, the organizer, said yes. Greatly helped by few colleagues (Mårten Möller, Tindy Hellman, Bruno Mikus, Brittany Pinder...) we ran a first event in November 2017 with a connection between London and Stockholm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x01:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a full video of the first event (Distributed C++ Meetup 0x01) where we had lightning talks from speakers on both sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vIVZsVneVDg" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or if you want to see some specific talks, you can also watch this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLBKFkLKL89uLmO22p7vWVrWO5eGzDM7PE"&gt;youtube playlist&lt;/a&gt; with videos nicely crafted by our amazing &lt;strong&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/strong&gt; video crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty nervous to be the host of the event, but I think that everything ran pretty smoothly and the vast majority of the attendees enjoyed the concept. 
We had few learnings though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people prefer the long format for the talks instead of lightning talks we used this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a failed attempt in creating an interaction between the crowd and the speakers. No one really dares to speak to remote speakers! This could be solved by using apps like slido.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It always nice to use have backups for video recording and sound recording. The audio recorded in London was not as good as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not drink the beers and ciders originally bought for the halloween party!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I decided to write about this event few months after is that 1) I am lazy 2) we will soon have another run of this concept.
Next week, on the 28th of March 2018, the Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02 will happen. This time not only London and Stockholm will be involved but we also bring with us the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/berlincplusplus/"&gt;Berlin Meetup Group&lt;/a&gt; managed by Sebastian Theophil and Vasil Georgiev (from King)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this post and want to join the event, it is still not too late to sign-up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/berlincplusplus/events/248093069/"&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/CppLondon/events/248091281/"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/events/248092613/"&gt;Stockholm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="C++ Stockholm London Berlin Distributed Meetup"></category></entry><entry><title>C++ Stockholm 0x02</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2017-02-20:/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to participate last week in a &lt;strong&gt;C++ meetup&lt;/strong&gt;.
This &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm meetup group&lt;/a&gt; is fairly recent but has a lot of potential!
I am always enjoying my time during these sessions, surrounded by the smart and passionated people.
In the unlikely chance that you are living around …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to participate last week in a &lt;strong&gt;C++ meetup&lt;/strong&gt;.
This &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm meetup group&lt;/a&gt; is fairly recent but has a lot of potential!
I am always enjoying my time during these sessions, surrounded by the smart and passionated people.
In the unlikely chance that you are living around &lt;strong&gt;Stockholm&lt;/strong&gt;, or decided to visit the capital of Scandinavia (and start missing your keyboard), I would highly recommend you to join this group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second edition of our conference &lt;strong&gt;C++ Stockholm 0x02&lt;/strong&gt;, I volunteered for talk about a subject I already adressed in the blog: &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/sfinae-introduction.html"&gt;SFINAE and compile-time introspection&lt;/a&gt;.
Overall, it was a good exercise for a first talk but I definitely need more training :). 
I discovered that it is much harder than I expected to explain code in live.
Thanks to the meetup team, I have a video of this talk with a very nice editing job done on it. 
It is always a weird experience to watch yourself on a video and was not so keen to put it here in the first place. 
But since this video has already &lt;em&gt;leaked&lt;/em&gt; among my friends (or foes in that case) and colleagues, I guess I might place it for the posterity!
So, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YgbTBqS-bHg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a pdf version of the slides right &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/images/SFINAE-compile-time-introspection.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog C++17 C++ Stockholm"></category></entry><entry><title>Why starting this blog?</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-17T21:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-10-17T21:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2015-10-17:/blogs/tech/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whilst I never had an urge to daily browse the various social networks, I have always liked to read technical articles and to follow few blogs. I wanted, since few years, to write my thoughts somewhere in order to clarify them and be able to easily fetch them later on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whilst I never had an urge to daily browse the various social networks, I have always liked to read technical articles and to follow few blogs. I wanted, since few years, to write my thoughts somewhere in order to clarify them and be able to easily fetch them later on. I procrastinated the idea of running a tech blog for few years, my aversion for the over-engineered web technologies and a lack of motivation restrained me. However, I have more spare time these days and I stumbled upon a simple and elegant Python static blog generator called &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. With &lt;strong&gt;Pelican&lt;/strong&gt; I don't have to pull a thousand of npm packages for a sanatizing function neither to use the latest language for hipsters with an eccentric syntax. Static pages also greatly simplify the maintenance and decrease the security burdens of dynamic websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this blog is mostly for my own purpose, I also hope that I could get an external opinion on my posts, my methods or even my skills in the beautiful English language.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>