<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jean Guegant's Blog - News</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/feeds/news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/</id><updated>2018-04-07T21:04:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup-0x02.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-07T21:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-04-07T21:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2018-04-07:/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup-0x02.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick follow-up of the event I announced in my previous &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;: the &lt;strong&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02&lt;/strong&gt;. A quick explanation for those too lazy to click a link or scroll down a bit to read my previous post (not judging you here, I would do the same); the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick follow-up of the event I announced in my previous &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;: the &lt;strong&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02&lt;/strong&gt;. A quick explanation for those too lazy to click a link or scroll down a bit to read my previous post (not judging you here, I would do the same); the concept of a Distibuted C++ Meetup consists in gathering multiple C++ user groups from around the world in one event using video-conference facilities. This time we had the pleasure to bring together the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/berlincplusplus/"&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/CppLondon/"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm&lt;/a&gt; Meetup groups using &lt;a href="https://king.com/"&gt;King's&lt;/a&gt; offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again &lt;strong&gt;Phil Nash&lt;/strong&gt; took on himself to edit a full footage of the event, which you can enjoy right here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/31mQmUryw50" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have altenative footage of the two first talks made by &lt;strong&gt;Harald Achitz&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="300" height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Os3i-N_Pz2U" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="300" height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NGrnKr9rSz4" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the host of the event makes you easily distracted, and so I was! But thanks to Phil's and Harald's work, I can enjoy a rewatch of the talks in a serene environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harald Achitz&lt;/strong&gt; gently explained us the &lt;a href="http://open-std.org/JTC1/SC22/WG21/docs/papers/2017/p0515r0.pdf"&gt;space-ship operator&lt;/a&gt; that will arrive in C++20 and what to expect from it. Then came the introduction on &lt;strong&gt;Type Safe Flags&lt;/strong&gt; made by &lt;strong&gt;Arvid Norberg&lt;/strong&gt; that I particulary enjoyed : simple and very practical! &lt;strong&gt;Richard Spindler&lt;/strong&gt; related us his experience with &lt;a href="https://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_66_0/libs/compute/doc/html/index.html"&gt;Boost.Compute&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, &lt;strong&gt;Dominic Jones&lt;/strong&gt; made a talk on &lt;strong&gt;Expression Tree Transform&lt;/strong&gt; which reminded me a lot &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QYNRoeWJuAw"&gt;Reactive Equations by André Bergner&lt;/a&gt; that I had the chance to see during &lt;strong&gt;Meeting C++ 2017&lt;/strong&gt;. Although, I always enjoy template meta-programming, it was very alien to anyone at the event who wasn't familiar to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expression_templates"&gt;expression templates&lt;/a&gt;. I always admire anyone willing to be on stage to share her/his knowledge and I appreciate the honor our speakers did to us by doing so that evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Polirazed opinions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the tradition goes, we sent a survey after our Meetup event. The feedback we received was substantially more divided than last time. Although the numbers indicate that a majority of the people are willing to redo such an event ; 47.50% really want a re-run, 35.00% liked it as much as a normal event, 17.50% would have prefer to stick to a normal one; it was clearly less popular than the last event with respectively 82.50%, 15% and 2%. Surprisingly people changed their minds and now would prefer going back to lightning talks (instead of 30min ones), as suggested by few feedback comments. As a comparison you can also read more about the previous event's results on Phil Nash's &lt;a href="http://www.levelofindirection.com/journal/2017/11/6/the-worlds-first-distributed-c-meet-up.html"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. People also expressed a strong feeling of being less "connected with the remote crowd" this time, which is sadly one of our main goal for a Distributed Meetup. It was especially surprising that this time we had questions crossing the virtual borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reflecting on what changed in our event's recipe and what could have be done better. Here are my thoughs as well as observations from other co-organizers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more cities we gather, the less time each location has talks happening physically in front of them. No matter how good is the video-conference setup, anyone would prefer to have it "at home". While as an attendee you will appreciate spending &lt;strong&gt;half&lt;/strong&gt; of the event learning from speakers at another location, &lt;strong&gt;two-thirds&lt;/strong&gt; of the event might be too long. Having more cities also increase the risk of cumulating technical issues. I would suggest to come back to a two cities format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to have room for a break in our schedule. Even Supertemplateman would not stand two hours of C++ talks on a cramped bench. Having 15min to make our transitions between countries would be pretty sweet too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightning talks may be somehow frustrating as they barely touch the surface of a topic. But a 35min talk can also be pretty damn long if you do not like the subject, even more so when projected on a screen. We would like to try 15min for a next run of the event. Shorter talks also have a desirable side effect: speakers will tend to write slides that are very expressive. Which bring us to the next issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I noticed that slides were much harder to read especially on the weird 4-TVs setup we have in the Stockholm's office. This was corroborated by the feedback specific to Stockholm. Tiny fonts force you to concentrate to extrapolate information that you cannot obtain with your eyes, it's exhausting and frustrating. We should really advise the speakers to use a minimum font size prior to the event. There is also the possibility to have multiple screens in the Stockholm office, to improve the experience for the people that always sit in our very attractive carousels in the back (every King employee did that mistake once).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People don't like the mandatory NDA to access the London office. I am not sure how this could be solved, as I am not familiar to this office. Be sure that we will explore that topic later on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, as a reminder, never forget to turn the light on! As much as we are used to darkness in Sweden, it was still a challenge for us to see what happened in the tenebrous London office. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to run a third &lt;strong&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup&lt;/strong&gt; with the aforementioned "bug-fixes". I am eager to see if the concept is actually viable or if the first run was simply benefiting from the novelty effect. As we are pioneer in these virtual meetups, it is pretty obvious that we will have to &lt;s&gt;use our attendees as guinea pigs&lt;/s&gt; slowly refine our ideas .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all people that helped during this event: Mårten Möller, Vasil Georgiev, Phil Nash, Harald Achitz, Tindy Hellman, Bruno Mikus, our tech and video-crew...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="C++ Stockholm London Berlin Distributed Meetup"></category></entry><entry><title>Distributed C++ Meetup</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-20T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2018-03-20:/blogs/tech/distributed-c++-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in an early &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I am active member of a C++ Meetup group in Stockholm: &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/a&gt;. Last year me and the main organizer of &lt;strong&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/strong&gt; came up with the idea to gather different Meetup groups from Europe for a special event. Knowing that we are not as famous …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in an early &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I am active member of a C++ Meetup group in Stockholm: &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/a&gt;. Last year me and the main organizer of &lt;strong&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/strong&gt; came up with the idea to gather different Meetup groups from Europe for a special event. Knowing that we are not as famous as the &lt;a href="https://cppcon.org/"&gt;cppcon&lt;/a&gt;, and therefore could not attract people easily to come to visit us in our dark and cold country, we had to come up with a special plan. It happens that my current company &lt;a href="https://discover.king.com/about/"&gt;King&lt;/a&gt; has offices of decent size in few of the major tech hubs of Europe: Berlin, Stockholm, London and Barcelona. It also happens that we have pretty good video-conference facilities that we frequently use to do company-wide calls. AND It also happens that a huge share of the mobile games (Candy Crush Saga, Bubble Witch Saga...) made at &lt;strong&gt;King&lt;/strong&gt; rely heavily on a &lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt; tech stack. By using the video-conference facilities, having some drinks and food, all gently provided by &lt;strong&gt;King&lt;/strong&gt;, we were confident that we could run an event with multiple Meetup groups participating remotely and have a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus was born the concept of a &lt;strong&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We contacted the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/CppLondon/events/248091281/"&gt;London Meetup group&lt;/a&gt; and asked them if they wanted to join us in this aventure. Sure enough, Phil Nash, the organizer, said yes. Greatly helped by few colleagues (Mårten Möller, Tindy Hellman, Bruno Mikus, Brittany Pinder...) we ran a first event in November 2017 with a connection between London and Stockholm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x01:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a full video of the first event (Distributed C++ Meetup 0x01) where we had lightning talks from speakers on both sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vIVZsVneVDg" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or if you want to see some specific talks, you can also watch this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLBKFkLKL89uLmO22p7vWVrWO5eGzDM7PE"&gt;youtube playlist&lt;/a&gt; with videos nicely crafted by our amazing &lt;strong&gt;SwedenCpp&lt;/strong&gt; video crew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty nervous to be the host of the event, but I think that everything ran pretty smoothly and the vast majority of the attendees enjoyed the concept. 
We had few learnings though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people prefer the long format for the talks instead of lightning talks we used this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a failed attempt in creating an interaction between the crowd and the speakers. No one really dares to speak to remote speakers! This could be solved by using apps like slido.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It always nice to use have backups for video recording and sound recording. The audio recorded in London was not as good as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not drink the beers and ciders originally bought for the halloween party!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I decided to write about this event few months after is that 1) I am lazy 2) we will soon have another run of this concept.
Next week, on the 28th of March 2018, the Distributed C++ Meetup 0x02 will happen. This time not only London and Stockholm will be involved but we also bring with us the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/berlincplusplus/"&gt;Berlin Meetup Group&lt;/a&gt; managed by Sebastian Theophil and Vasil Georgiev (from King)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this post and want to join the event, it is still not too late to sign-up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/berlincplusplus/events/248093069/"&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/CppLondon/events/248091281/"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/events/248092613/"&gt;Stockholm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="C++ Stockholm London Berlin Distributed Meetup"></category></entry><entry><title>C++ Stockholm 0x02</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2017-02-20:/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to participate last week in a &lt;strong&gt;C++ meetup&lt;/strong&gt;.
This &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm meetup group&lt;/a&gt; is fairly recent but has a lot of potential!
I am always enjoying my time during these sessions, surrounded by the smart and passionated people.
In the unlikely chance that you are living around …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to participate last week in a &lt;strong&gt;C++ meetup&lt;/strong&gt;.
This &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm meetup group&lt;/a&gt; is fairly recent but has a lot of potential!
I am always enjoying my time during these sessions, surrounded by the smart and passionated people.
In the unlikely chance that you are living around &lt;strong&gt;Stockholm&lt;/strong&gt;, or decided to visit the capital of Scandinavia (and start missing your keyboard), I would highly recommend you to join this group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second edition of our conference &lt;strong&gt;C++ Stockholm 0x02&lt;/strong&gt;, I volunteered for talk about a subject I already adressed in the blog: &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/sfinae-introduction.html"&gt;SFINAE and compile-time introspection&lt;/a&gt;.
Overall, it was a good exercise for a first talk but I definitely need more training :). 
I discovered that it is much harder than I expected to explain code in live.
Thanks to the meetup team, I have a video of this talk with a very nice editing job done on it. 
It is always a weird experience to watch yourself on a video and was not so keen to put it here in the first place. 
But since this video has already &lt;em&gt;leaked&lt;/em&gt; among my friends (or foes in that case) and colleagues, I guess I might place it for the posterity!
So, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YgbTBqS-bHg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a pdf version of the slides right &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/images/SFINAE-compile-time-introspection.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog C++17 C++ Stockholm"></category></entry><entry><title>Why starting this blog?</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-17T21:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-10-17T21:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2015-10-17:/blogs/tech/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whilst I never had an urge to daily browse the various social networks, I have always liked to read technical articles and to follow few blogs. I wanted, since few years, to write my thoughts somewhere in order to clarify them and be able to easily fetch them later on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whilst I never had an urge to daily browse the various social networks, I have always liked to read technical articles and to follow few blogs. I wanted, since few years, to write my thoughts somewhere in order to clarify them and be able to easily fetch them later on. I procrastinated the idea of running a tech blog for few years, my aversion for the over-engineered web technologies and a lack of motivation restrained me. However, I have more spare time these days and I stumbled upon a simple and elegant Python static blog generator called &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. With &lt;strong&gt;Pelican&lt;/strong&gt; I don't have to pull a thousand of npm packages for a sanatizing function neither to use the latest language for hipsters with an eccentric syntax. Static pages also greatly simplify the maintenance and decrease the security burdens of dynamic websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this blog is mostly for my own purpose, I also hope that I could get an external opinion on my posts, my methods or even my skills in the beautiful English language.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>