<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jean Guegant's Blog - News</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/feeds/news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/</id><updated>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>C++ Stockholm 0x02</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T21:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2017-02-20:/blogs/tech/c++-stockholm-0x02.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to participate last week in a &lt;strong&gt;C++ meetup&lt;/strong&gt;.
This &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm meetup group&lt;/a&gt; is fairly recent but has a lot of potential!
I am always enjoying my time during these sessions, surrounded by the smart and passionated people.
In the unlikely chance that you are living around …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to participate last week in a &lt;strong&gt;C++ meetup&lt;/strong&gt;.
This &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/swedencpp/"&gt;Stockholm meetup group&lt;/a&gt; is fairly recent but has a lot of potential!
I am always enjoying my time during these sessions, surrounded by the smart and passionated people.
In the unlikely chance that you are living around &lt;strong&gt;Stockholm&lt;/strong&gt;, or decided to visit the capital of Scandinavia (and start missing your keyboard), I would highly recommend you to join this group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second edition of our conference &lt;strong&gt;C++ Stockholm 0x02&lt;/strong&gt;, I volunteered for talk about a subject I already adressed in the blog: &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/sfinae-introduction.html"&gt;SFINAE and compile-time introspection&lt;/a&gt;.
Overall, it was a good exercise for a first talk but I definitely need more training :). 
I discovered that it is much harder than I expected to explain code in live.
Thanks to the meetup team, I have a video of this talk with a very nice editing job done on it. 
It is always a weird experience to watch yourself on a video and was not so keen to put it here in the first place. 
But since this video has already &lt;em&gt;leaked&lt;/em&gt; among my friends (or foes in that case) and colleagues, I guess I might place it for the posterity!
So, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YgbTBqS-bHg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a pdf version of the slides right &lt;a href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/images/SFINAE-compile-time-introspection.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog C++17 C++ Stockholm"></category></entry><entry><title>Why starting this blog?</title><link href="//jguegant.github.io/blogs/tech/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-17T21:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-10-17T21:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jean Guegant</name></author><id>tag:jguegant.github.io,2015-10-17:/blogs/tech/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whilst I never had an urge to daily browse the various social networks, I have always liked to read technical articles and to follow few blogs. I wanted, since few years, to write my thoughts somewhere in order to clarify them and be able to easily fetch them later on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whilst I never had an urge to daily browse the various social networks, I have always liked to read technical articles and to follow few blogs. I wanted, since few years, to write my thoughts somewhere in order to clarify them and be able to easily fetch them later on. I procrastinated the idea of running a tech blog for few years, my aversion for the over-engineered web technologies and a lack of motivation restrained me. However, I have more spare time these days and I stumbled upon a simple and elegant Python static blog generator called &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. With &lt;strong&gt;Pelican&lt;/strong&gt; I don't have to pull a thousand of npm packages for a sanatizing function neither to use the latest language for hipsters with an eccentric syntax. Static pages also greatly simplify the maintenance and decrease the security burdens of dynamic websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this blog is mostly for my own purpose, I also hope that I could get an external opinion on my posts, my methods or even my skills in the beautiful English language.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>